mtv.co.uk 2011-12-02

# Privacy Policy | MTV UK

**  
**  
This Privacy Policy sets out how we and our related companies use any personal information that you give to us or we collect from you, such as your name, address, telephone number or email address. Personal information also includes anything else that can identify you as an individual, such as photos or videos of you and any information regarding your interests, hobbies, preferences or other similar information which we link to your personal information. We refer to this as “ **your information** ” in this privacy policy. 

We may give certain words that are used in this Privacy Policy a particular meaning which will be set out where these words are featured in bold within inverted commas like this:  “ **words** ”.

**1.      ****OUR DETAILS**

" **We** ", " **us** " and " **our** " means MTV Networks Europe which is a Delaware partnership between MTV Networks Europe Inc and Viacom Networks Europe. Our principal place of business is at 17-29 Hawley Crescent, London NW1 8TT. Our VAT number is GB466509032. If you have any questions or concerns please refer to our _[frequently answered questions](http://www.mtv.co.uk/terms/faq)_[(“](http://www.mtv.co.uk/terms/faq) **[FAQs](http://www.mtv.co.uk/terms/faq)**[”).](http://www.mtv.co.uk/terms/faq)  If the FAQs do not adequately address your questions or concerns you may contact us using our _[email contact form](http://www.mtv.co.uk/contact)_[.](http://www.mtv.co.uk/contact)

**2.      ****CHANGES TO THIS POLICY**

We may need to make changes to this privacy policy in future. For example to reflect changes in the law, changes in the type of services or information we provide to you or to correct any errors. We will try to keep all such changes to a minimum. We recommend that you check this policy from time to time to see if it has changed. We will always state at the bottom of this policy the date on which it was last updated.

If you continue to use our services after our privacy policy changes you will be bound by those changes.

**3.      ****HOW WE COLLECT YOUR INFORMATION**

We collect your information in the following ways. 

·       When you give it to us, for example when you:

-        provide information about yourself to enter one of our competitions or promotions

-        order products or services from us such as video clips from our WAP site (see our _[Mobile Terms of Use](http://www.mtv.co.uk/terms/mobile)_  for more information on the use of our mobile services)

-        register as a new member of one of our online communities (See our [“](http://www.mtv.co.uk/terms/privacy#socialproject) _[Online Communities and Social Project”](http://www.mtv.co.uk/terms/privacy#socialproject)_ section below and our _[Website Terms of Use](http://www.mtv.co.uk/terms/website)_ for more information on this registration process)

-        opt in to receive any of our newsletters or other marketing information

-        rate  or post any comments regarding content cast a vote on anything within our online services 

-        register to access paid premium content on our MTV OD service

·       If it is passed to us by Social Project Inc when you join one of our online communities from another community within the Social Project Network (see [“](http://www.mtv.co.uk/terms/privacy#socialproject) _[Our Online Communities and Social Project](http://www.mtv.co.uk/terms/privacy#socialproject)_[”](http://www.mtv.co.uk/terms/privacy#socialproject) Section below and the _[SP Privacy Policy](http://www.socialproject.com/PrivacyPolicy.html)_ for more details on this) 

·       If it passed to us by our affiliates, partners or other third parties with your consent

·       Automatically using “ **cookies** ”, web beacons and other tracking systems (see the [“](http://www.mtv.co.uk/terms/privacy#automatic) _[Automatic Information](http://www.mtv.co.uk/terms/privacy#automatic)_[”](http://www.mtv.co.uk/terms/privacy#automatic) section below for more details on how we use cookies and how you can disable them if you choose to do so). 

**4.      ****HOW WE USE AND DISCLOSE YOUR INFORMATION**

We use your information operationally to:

·       process any requests or orders for goods or services that you may have requested or purchased ** __**

·       to enter you for the competitions or promotions which you have indicated you wish to enter, **__**

·       identify your personal preferences for any communications to you such as newsletters ** __**

·       provide you with access to any of our online communities that you are a member of and to provide you with updates relating to those communities ** __**

·       allow you to post comments, rate content or cast your vote ** __**

·       to respond to or deal with any queries or complaints that you may have ** __**

In addition and with your consent we (and if applicable, our partners or other trusted third parties) use your information for certain marketing, market research, analysis and related purposes. It is up to you how much or how little information you allow us to use for these purposes. Our on screen notices will ask for your explicit permission (often by way of a tick box) for such additional purposes. These purposes include: 

·       to communicate with you from time to time by email,  by mobile (using SMS or, if your mobile device permits, MMS messages or similar technologies) with updates regarding any account you may have with us or services you have requested from us (i.e. MTV OD)

·       to communicate with you from time to time by email,  by mobile (using SMS or, if your mobile device permits, MMS messages or similar technologies) and occasionally by post with our newsletters, information, offers and other material which may interest you (such communications may be sent by third party service providers on our behalf)

·       to make your information available from time to time to trusted partners and third parties, for the same purposes as above (which will be in accordance with the privacy policies of such trusted partners and third parties)

·       to conduct market research, for example by asking you to participate in a survey about topical issues conducted by us or trusted partners or third parties. We will always try to tell you before you participate in the survey how any information you provide in the survey will be used 

·       to enable us and third parties acting on our behalf to analyse your information, in a non-identifying form, (generally in the form of statistics), so that we can identify trends about usage of our online or other services and improve them 

We also reserve the right to access and disclose your personal information in order to comply with applicable laws, to comply with lawful requests from governments, law enforcement agencies or parties whose request we reasonably consider to be justified in connection with any allegations by any party about your abuse of our services, to operate our systems properly or to protect ourselves or our users. 

Some of the partners and third parties with whom we share your information for the purposes set out above may be outside of the European Union and in countries which may provide a lower standard of protection for personal data, by using our online services you consent to the transfer of your personal information outside of the EU.

**5.      ****OUR ONLINE COMMUNITIES AND SOCIAL PROJECT**

All of our online communities and your member profiles for those communities are powered, hosted, and administered by Social Project Inc (“ **SP** ”) which is a company based in the United States that operates a website at [http://www.socialproject.com](http://www.socialproject.com/) and a global network of online social communities (“ **SP Network** ”). 

When you submit your information to join any of our communities you automatically register with both that community and directly with SP in the United States. The use by us of your registered information shall be in accordance with this Privacy Policy whereas the use by SP of your information is governed by the _[SP Privacy Policy](http://www.socialproject.com/PrivacyPolicy.html)_[ (click here to see how SP makes use of your personal data)](http://www.socialproject.com/PrivacyPolicy.html) and United States law.  Please note that United States law provides a lower standard of protection for personal information than the United Kingdom.  By registering with, using and participating in any of our communities you therefore acknowledge and consent to the submission, collection, transfer, storage, and processing of your information to and in the United States.

Once you are registered with any of our online communities you may easily join any other community within the SP Network by simply clicking the join button within that website. On joining that other community your user profile information will be automatically transferred by SP to that other community. You may also be required to provide additional information and/or consents.  Please note that the use of your information by the operator of that community (which may be in a different country) will be subject its privacy policy (which you should review) and shall be governed by the local laws of its country and we shall have no responsibility for this.

Your member profiles within the SP Network are public (unless made private) as are postings to any of our communities which can be indexed by third-party search engines and appear in search results on third-party web sites. You should therefore exercise caution when disclosing information in your profile or elsewhere on any of our communities. 

You can decide how much of your information is automatically displayed in your public profile as follows: 

  * You can hide certain of elements of your member profile information by revising the member privacy settings found in the “Privacy” page of the “Profile” area (found by clicking on the “Profile” tab and then the “Edit Profile” tab and then “Privacy”). IMPORTANT NOTE: Even if you set your member profile to private your thumbnail picture, display name, general location, and gender may still appear publicly: (i) as a search result if another Member conducts a search of other SP Network communities using matching criteria, such as location, gender, age criteria, etc.; and (ii) on other SP Network communities that display featured thumbnails, for example, pages showing most active members, recent members, most popular members, etc  

·       You can choose to completely hide from public view posts to your member profile blog

·       You can delete comments posted to another community member’s page. 

Please refer to our _[Website Terms of Use](http://www.mtv.co.uk/terms/website)_ for restrictions with respect to public postings.  We reserve the right (in our sole discretion) to set certain limits on the availability of some or all features within our communities.

**6.      ****UNSUBSCRIBING/ AMENDING YOUR INFORMATION / NEWSLETTERS**

You can amend or remove information you give us via our online services at any time as follows:

·       to amend any information you have given us when registering for our online communities  go to your member profile area by clicking on the “profile” tab and then select “Edit Profile” and you can amend your basic information, personal preferences (which will affect what content we include in our newsletters and marketing information sent to you) and profile photo

·       to deactivate your member account click go to the Profile area and select on “Edit Profile” and then “Account” and then click on the relevant link 

·       to unsubscribe from a newsletter or other email distribution click on the relevant link on the newsletter/other email (which can normally be found at the bottom of the communication) or go the “Preferences” area of our online services and remove the ticks from the newsletters boxes

·       to withdraw from a subscription service you requested via SMS/MMS (as opposed to online) by following the instructions you receive in the message confirming your request and sending the message “STOP” to the appropriate short code (see the _[Mobile Services Terms of Use](http://www.mtv.co.uk/terms/mobile)_ for more detail on this). 

If you want to remove all of your information from our database or have any questions about privacy issues, you can contact us by using our _[email contact form](http://www.mtv.co.uk/contact)_ specifying your name, user-name, email address and telephone number and asking for your information to be removed or specifying any questions you may have. 

**7.      ****AUTOMATIC INFORMATION**

Like many websites, we use "cookies”. Cookies are small text files that websites automatically save to the cookie file of the browser on your computer when you enter the website. We do not use cookies that access any information stored on your hard drive or damage or otherwise endanger your computer. We use cookies to identify your computer when you use our online services and to track and assist your navigation around our online services. 

Examples of the information that may be analysed using cookies are user-name, email address and password, the internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the internet, browser type and version, operating system and platform you use to connect, areas of our online services that you viewed or searched for, the Uniform Resource Locators (URLs) from or through which you entered and exited our online services and the date and time of such activity. 

You can use the "Help" section of the tool bar on most browsers to change the settings on your computer, for example to notify you when you receive a cookie, or to refuse all cookies. However, some of the features of our online services may not work or may be more difficult to access if you refuse all cookies. If you want to find out more about cookies go to [www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/).

We use third party advertising companies to serve advertisements on our online services including a company known as DoubleClick and Google’s AdSense program. The ads you receive are influenced by various factors, including your browsing history prior to visiting this website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your use of our online services in order to provide advertisements about goods and services that may be of interest to you. In the course of serving advertisements, our third party serving network may place or recognise a unique "cookie" on your browser. This is a "persistent" cookie, which means that it is stored on your computer and will remain there until it expires or you remove it. The ad serving networks may also make use of other technologies, such as "web beacons", in order to improve the relevance of the ads you receive.  If you would like more information about DoubleClick’s practices and to know your choices about not having this information used by this company please click here: _[www.doubleclick.net/us/corporate/privacy](http://www.doubleclick.net/us/corporate/privacy)_. If you would like more information about Google’s AdSense program please click here: [www.google.com/adsense](http://www.google.com/adsense). ** __**

**8.      ****SECURITY**

We have taken steps to ensure that your personal information is secure, including limiting the number of people who have physical access to our database servers, as well as electronic security systems and password protections that guard against unauthorised access. 

**9.      ****BUSINESS TRANSFERS**

In the unlikely event that we sell or otherwise dispose of some or all of our business to another party, we reserve the right to transfer your information as part of any assets sold or disposed of and you consent to such transfer. 

This policy was last updated on 9th June 2011.
